Guide to the J. Deryl Hart Records, 1957 - 1980 (bulk 1960-1963) UA.03.58.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Deryl Hart records
1957 - 1980 (bulk 1960-1963)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hart, Deryl, 1894-1980
UA.03.58.0001
20 Linear Feet
Julian Deryl Hart (1894-1980), was Professor and Chairman of the Department of Surgery at Duke University from 1930-1960 and President of the University from 1960-1963. As President, Hart dealt with the affairs of administration; organized the Provost group to share in governance of the University; and significantly redefined the responsibilities of the university's administrative offices. During Hart's presidency, faculty salaries and professorships increased, and the admissions policy was amended to make it more equitable. Hart was an active member of the Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School. The J. Deryl Hart Records contain subject files from Hart's office files as President of Duke University and annual reports from university offices and departments to the President. Materials include correspondence, published reports, manuscripts, memos, clippings, copies of speeches and addresses, and other types of printed material. Major subjects include the development of the university and the Medical Center, the reorganization of the university's administrative offices, and the advancement of the faculty. English.
20,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
The Clipping File, Folder 33, is not immediately accessible because it requires further processing before use.
Provenance
The J. Deryl Hart Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1967 (A67-325), 1974 (A74-124), 1983 (A83-6) and a gift in 2000 (A2000-87).
Biographical Note
Julian Deryl Hart (1894-1980), surgeon and university president, was born in Prattsburg, Ga. He attended Emory University (A.B., 1916; A.M., 1917) and John Hopkins School of Medicine (M.D., 1921). Hart continued on at Johns Hopkins in surgery and pathology from 1921-1930. Hart came to Duke University in 1930 as professor of surgery and chairman of the department in the Duke University School of Medicine and Hospital. At Duke, Hart led in the development of the private diagnostic clinics and his pioneering work on the use of ultraviolet radiation as a way to combat airborne infections in the operating room won national acclaim.
Hart retired from the medical faculty to become president pro tem of Duke University in April, 1960. The Board of Trustees appointed him president, retroactive to that date. Hart brought to the university, then in a period of administrative turmoil, a concept of leadership defined by the need for teamwork. During his presidency, the relationships among trustees, administrators, and faculty were reorganized to eliminate conflict and tension. Hart also presided over major expansions of the university campus. Under his leadership, faculty salaries were raised substantially and the number of endowed professorships doubled. Hart retired from the presidency in 1963.
Hart married Mary Elizabeth Johnson of Raleigh in 1932. They had six children. Hart was an active Democrat and a member of the Methodist Church.
[Portions of this text are taken from William S. Powell's Dictionary of North Carolina Biography, Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, c1979-1996.]
Collection Overview
The J. Deryl Hart Records contain subject files from Hart's office files as President of Duke University and annual reports from university offices and departments to the President. Materials include correspondence, published reports, manuscripts, memos, clippings, copies of speeches and addresses, and other types of printed material. Major subjects include the development of the university and the Medical Center, the reorganization of the university's administrative offices, and the advancement of the faculty.
Access to Folders 117, 129, 142, 143, 145, 146, 565, 579, 580, and 584 is RESTRICTED. Please consult University Archives staff.
Two additions were made to the collection, in 1983 (A83-6) and in 2000 (A2000-87). These additions are separate series and are cataloged at the end of the finding aid.
Please consult the Duke University Medical Center Archives for materials that document Hart's career as a professor of surgery and Chairman of the Dept. of Surgery.
Related Material
Duke University Board of Trustees Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University Faculty Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
[Forms part of:] Duke University President Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
J. Deryl Hart Collection.
Medical Center Archives, Duke University.
North Carolina. Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School; Physicians -- North Carolina; Clippings (information artifacts); Universities and colleges -- North Carolina; Hart, Deryl, 1894-1980; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Faculty -- History; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Presidents; Duke University. Medical Center. Dept. of Surgery; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Presidents; Duke University. Medical Center; Hart, Deryl, 1894-1980; Duke University
- Subject Files, 1960-1980
  Scope and Contents note
  The subject files include the President's Office's records. Major subjects include Hart's involvement in various professional organizations; the development and daily business of Duke University; the Medical Center; and Hart's involvement on the N.C. Governor's Commission on Education Beyond the High School. As President, Hart significantly redefined the responsibilities of university's administrative offices. During Hart's presidency, faculty salaries and professorships increased, and the admissions policy was amended to make it more equitable. The subject files include materials that document these changes within the university. Materials include correspondence, published reports, manuscripts, memos, clippings, copies of speeches and addresses, and other types of printed material.
  Access to Folders 117, 129, 140-143, and 145-146 is RESTRICTED. Please consult University Archives staff.
  - Shelf List of Folder Titles (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ackland Museum, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, George Garland, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Alumni Council, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Assembly, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Bankers Association, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Council on Education
    - 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Physical Society, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Security Council, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Army Research Office (Durham), 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Association of American Universities (Box 2)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Association of NROTC Colleges, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Association of Universities of the British Commonwealth, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Associations, Miscellaneous, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Atlantic Coast Conference, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - B Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Boy's Club of Durham, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brinkley, William L., 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Bryson, Edwin Constant, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - C Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cleland, James Tough, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Brittle newsprint may need to be reformatted for use. Please contact University Archives staff before use.
  - Cole, Robert Taylor (Provost), 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - College Celebrations, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - College Presidencies, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Communism (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc., 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Council of Graduate Schools in the United States, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Council of Southern Universities
    - 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Crank Letters
    - 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Cresap, McCormick and Paget (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - D Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Davison, Wilburt Cornell
    - 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - deVyver, Frank Traver, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Duke, Doris (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Duke Endowment
    - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Committee on Educational Institutions (Box 6, Folder 55-56)
    - Duke University Open Account (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Rural Church Section, 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Superannuate Fund (Box 7)
      - 1960 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - 1961 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - 1962 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Duke Mathematical Journal, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Duke University
    - Academic Council (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Accreditations, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Administrative Committee (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Admissions, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Admissions Committee (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - African Studies Seminar, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Air Force ROTC, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Alcoholic Beverages (Policy), 1961 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Allocation of Space Committee (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Alumni Affairs
      - Bequest Program, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 72)
      - Dukes, Charles
        - 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 73)
        - 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 74)
      - Loyalty Fund, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 75)
      - Meetings, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Archives Committee (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Art Center (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Arts and Sciences, Dean Search Committee (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Artists Series (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Athletics (Box 9)
      - Athletic Council, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 81)
      - Football (Box 9, Folder 82)
      - 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Biophysics Committee (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Board of Trustees
      - Buildings and Grounds Committee (Box 9, Folder 85-87)
      - Bylaws Committee (Box 9, Folder 88)
      - Institutional Advancement Committee (Box 9, Folder 89)
      - Reports (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Budget Proposals (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Executive Committee (Box 10, Folder 589)
    - Buildings
      - 1960 (Box 10, Folder 92)
      - Building Needs, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 93)
      - Naming of Buildings, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - Bureau of Public Information (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Bureau of Testing and Guidance, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Business Office (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Calendar (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Campus Security Committee (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Center for the Study of Aging, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Duke Chapel
      - Administrative Committee (Box 10, Folder 101)
      - Crypt (Box 10, Folder 102)
      - Chaplains, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - Chronicle, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - Clock, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - Commencement (Box 11)
      - General Information (Box 11, Folder 106)
        Includes correspondence and information about commencement procedures.
      - Commencement Committee (Box 11, Folder 107)
      - Marshals (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - Committees, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1960-1963 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Contracts and Grants Committee (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Convocation, Christianity and Social Revolution (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - Cooperation with UNC, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Cooperative Program in Teacher Education (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Crystallography Laboratory, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Dad's Day, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 116)
    - Desegregation (Box 11, Folder 117)
      Access to folder 117 is RESTRICTED: Student records.
    - Development Office (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Distinguished Professors Committee (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Dormitories, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Divinity School, 1960-1963 (Box 12, Folder 121-122)
    - Dormitory Naming Committee (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - Dormitory Renovations Committee (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - Education Committee (Box 12, Folder 125)
    - Educational Administration Committee (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Educational Facilities Committee (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - Electronics Dept. (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - Employment Applications (Teaching), 1960-1963 (Box 12, Folder 129)
      Access to folder 129 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
    - Engineering School (Box 13, Folder 130-131)
    - Exchange Students, 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Facilities Committee (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Faculty
      - Buildings and Grounds Committee (Box 13, Folder 134)
      - Committees (Box 13, Folder 135)
      - Deceased and Retired (Box 13, Folder 136)
      - Elections Committee (Box 13, Folder 137)
      - Fringe Benefits Committee (Box 13, Folder 138)
      - Handbook (Box 13, Folder 139)
      - Leaves (Box 13, Folder 140-141)
        Access to folders 140-141 are RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
      - Leaves (Box 14, Folder 142-143)
        Access to folders 142-143 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
      - Reorganization Committee (Box 14, Folder 144)
      - Salaries (Box 14, Folder 145)
        Access to folder 145 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
      - Salary Letters (Box 14, Folder 146)
        Access to folder 146 is RESTRICTED: Personnel information.
      - Selection and Retention Committee (Box 14, Folder 147)
      - Trustee Liaison Committee (Box 14, Folder 148)
    - Fallout Preparedness Committee (Box 14, Folder 149-150)
    - Far Eastern Affairs Program, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 151)
    - Finances
      - Financial Aid Committee (Box 15, Folder 152)
      - Financial Data (Box 15, Folder 153-154)
      - Financial Needs (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Flag-Raising Ceremony (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Flowers Collection, 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Foreign Students Program Committee (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Foreign Visitors, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Forestry School (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Founders' Day (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Freshman Assembly, 1960-1962 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Gerontology Council (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Graduate Council (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - Graduate School (Box 15, Folder 165)
    - Humanities Council (Box 15, Folder 166)
    - Institutional Advancement, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - International Studies Committee (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Invitations to Seminars and Other Events (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - James B. Duke Professorships (Box 16, Folder 170)
    - Job Classification Study (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Law School
      - Reports and Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 172)
      - Law School Dedication, 1962-1963 (Box 16, Folder 173)
      - World Rule of Law Center (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - Library
      - 1960-1963 (Box 16, Folder 175)
      - Library Addition, 1960-1963 (Box 16, Folder 176)
      - Library Council (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - Linguistics Committee (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - Loans Committee (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - Long-Range Planning Committee (Box 17, Folder 180-195)
    - Marine Laboratory (Box 18, Folder 196)
    - Married Student Housing (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - Medical Center
      - Bank (Box 18, Folder 198)
      - Committee on Health Affairs, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 199)
      - Dermatology Department, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 200)
      - Ear, Nose, and Throat, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 201)
      - General Information, 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 202)
      - Gerontology, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 203)
      - Grants, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 204)
      - Hospital (Box 18, Folder 205)
      - Hospital Administration Program, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 206)
      - Hyperbaric Unit, 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 207)
      - Library, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 208)
      - Medical School (Box 18, Folder 209)
      - Medical School Dean: Barnes Woodhall
        - 1960-1962 (Box 18, Folder 210)
        - 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 211)
      - Medical School Fellowships (Box 19, Folder 212)
      - New Entrance Building, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 213)
      - Nursing School, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 214)
      - Outpatient Building Construction (Box 19, Folder 215)
      - Planning, 1960-1962 (Box 19, Folder 216)
      - Surgery Department, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 217)
      - Urological Surgery Division, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 218)
    - Men's Graduate Center (Box 19, Folder 219)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 220)
    - Naval ROTC, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 221)
    - Parking Committee (Box 19, Folder 222)
    - Patent Policy Committee (Box 19, Folder 223)
    - Parapsychology Laboratory, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 224)
    - Physical Education Committee (Box 20, Folder 225)
    - Phytotron (Box 20, Folder 226)
    - Presidential Selection Committee (Box 20, Folder 227)
    - President's Expenses (Box 20, Folder 228)
    - President's Report (3-Year) (Box 20, Folder 229-231)
    - President's Reports and Speeches (Box 20, Folder 232)
    - Provost Group (Box 20, Folder 233)
    - Public Education Committee (Box 20, Folder 234)
    - Publications Board (Box 20, Folder 235)
    - Radioisotopes Committee (Box 20, Folder 236)
    - Registrar: Statistics (Box 20, Folder 237)
    - Religious Council and Religious Life, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 238)
    - Research Grants, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 239)
    - Research Needs and Facilities, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 240)
    - Rhodes Scholarships Committee, 1961-1963 (Box 21, Folder 241)
    - Road Naming Committee (Box 21, Folder 242)
    - Roads, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 243)
    - Russian Affairs Committee (Box 21, Folder 244)
    - Schedule Committee (Box 21, Folder 245)
    - Scholarships Committee (Box 21, Folder 246)
    - Seminar, The Problems of Emerging Nations (Box 21, Folder 247)
    - Senior Class Gifts, 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 248)
    - Social Sciences Council (Box 21, Folder 249)
    - Sororities (Box 21, Folder 250)
    - Space Studies Committee (Box 21, Folder 251)
    - Space Symposium, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 252)
    - Staff Family Recreation Area (Box 21, Folder 253)
    - Statistical Operations Committee (Box 21, Folder 254)
    - Statistics (Box 21, Folder 255)
    - Students
      - Activities, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 256)
      - Student-Faculty-Administration Committee (Box 21, Folder 257)
      - Student Government, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 258)
      - Student Health (Box 21, Folder 259)
      - Student Health Facility (Box 21, Folder 260)
      - Statistics (Box 21, Folder 261)
    - Summer Session, 1960-1962 (Box 21, Folder 262)
    - Summer Theatre, 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 263)
    - Symposium, Crosscurrents in Contemporary Life, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 264)
    - Tuition Grants (Box 22, Folder 265)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 266)
    - University Council
      - Organization and Membership, July 1, 1960-March 7, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 267)
      - Minutes and Summaries, Sept. 21, 1960-June 19, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 268)
    - University House, Four Acres, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 269)
    - University Marshal, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - University Planning Committee
      - Educational Facilities Subcommittee (Box 22, Folder 271)
      - Educational Goals Subcommittee (Box 22, Folder 272)
      - Graduate Affairs Subcommittee (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Visiting Professors (Medical School) (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - Woman's College
      - Announcements and Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 276)
      - Dean Search Committee (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Women in Higher Education Conference (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Young Women's Christian Association (Box 22, Folder 279)
  - Duke University Press, 1960-1963 (Box 22, Folder 280)
  - DuPont Seminars, 1960-1962 (Box 23, Folder 281)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - E Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 283)
  - Eastern Air Lines (Box 23, Folder 284)
  - Edens, Arthur Hollis, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 285)
  - Education Legislation (Box 23, Folder 286)
  - Emory University, Elkins Lectureship (Box 23, Folder 287)
  - Engineering News-Report Network, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 288)
  - F Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 289)
  - Ford Foundation
    - General Correspondence and Reports (Box 23, Folder 290)
    - Asian Studies Grant (Box 23, Folder 291)
    - Cooperative Program in Teacher Education (Box 23, Folder 292)
    - Duke Press Grant (Box 23, Folder 293)
    - Economics Grant (Box 23, Folder 294)
    - Grant for Improvement of College Teaching (Box 23, Folder 295)
    - Profile (Box 23, Folder 296)
    - Public Affairs Grant (Box 23, Folder 297)
  - Foreign Students, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 298)
  - Foundation for Public Relations Research and Education, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Frenzel, Charles, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 300)
  - Fulbright Program (Box 24, Folder 301)
  - G Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 302)
  - Goucher College, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 303)
  - Gross, Paul M., 1963 (Box 24, Folder 304)
  - H Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 305)
  - Handler, Philip, 1960-1962 (Box 24, Folder 306)
  - Hart, Julian Deryl
    - Hart Testimonial Dinner, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 307)
    - Speeches and Writings (Box 24, Folder 308)
  - Herring, Herbert J., 1960-1963 (Box 24, Folder 309)
  - Highlander Center, Knoxville, Tenn., 1962 (Box 24, Folder 310)
  - Hobbs, Marcus E., 1960-1962 (Box 24, Folder 311)
  - Hopkins, Everett H. (Box 24, Folder 312-313)
  - Hopkins, Everett H. (Box 25, Folder 314-315)
  - I Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 316)
  - Institute of International Education (Box 25, Folder 317)
  - International Science Foundation, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 318)